Guide To the University Of California, Santa Cruz Contemporary Classical Collection ARS.0103
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 7" reels, 118 audiotape reel(s)
  - Schuller: String quartet. Imbrie: Legend for orchestra. Nono: Sul ponte di Hiroshima, circa 1965; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 11, Reel 103)
    This tape also contains dubbed copies of the following commercial releases: CBC Radio-Canada International Service, MG-838 (Kelsey Jones: Sonata Da Camera: Baroque Trio of CBC).
    Imbrie, Andrew, 1921-2007; Nono, Luigi; Jordá, Enrique; Pritchard, John, 1921-1989; London Symphony Orchestra; Schuller, Gunther; San Francisco Symphony Orchestra; Lewis, Richard, 1914-1990; Dorow, Dorothy
  - Hartmann: Symphony No.8. Harrison: Concerto for violin and percussion, circa 1965; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 11, Reel 104)
    Hartmann, Karl Amadeus, 1905-1963. Symphonies, no. 8. Cologne Radio Symphony, Maderna, conductor.
    Harrison, Lou, 1917-2003. Concertos, violin, percussion ensemble. Cabrillo Festival. August 22, 1965.
    This tape also contains dubbed copies of the following commercial releases: BMG Classics, 74321735092 (Zimmermann: Dialoge: Aloys and Alfano Kontarsky).
    Maderna, Bruno; Kölner Rundfunk-Sinfonie-Orchester; Hartmann, Karl Amadeus, 1905-1963; Harrison, Lou, 1917-2003
  - Toni Sailer, 1959; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 11, Reel 105)
    Songs performed by Toni Sailer. Includes Tiroler Hula-Hupp, and Immer wenn es schneit. Included with recording are sound engineer notes, and German to English translations for the lyrics for Tiroler Hula-Hupp, and Immer wenn es schneit. These lyric translations are typed on headed paper belonging to Radio-Klemt, and dated May 12, 1959.
    Sailer, Toni, 1935-2009
  - Maxfield, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 11, Reel 106)
    Interview with Richard Maxfield.
    Maxfield, Richard, 1927-1969. Concert suite from Dromenom. For 2 tape channels, with flute, saxophone, trombone, violin, cello, bass, vibraphone, and piano.
    Maxfield, Richard, 1927-1969. Perspective II for La Monte Young. Young, violin.
    Maxfield, Richard, 1927-1969. Piano concert for David Tudor.
    Maxfield, Richard, 1927-1969. Toy Symphony.
    Maxfield, Richard, 1927-1969; Young, La Monte
  - Interview with Alice Ehlers, 1961-10-16; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; full track] (Box 11, Reel 107)
    Interview with Alice Ehlers. Madison, WI.
    Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981
  - Byrd; Scarlatti; Bach; Rameau; Donatoni, circa 1962; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 11, Reel 108)
    Byrd, William, 1539 or 1540-1623. Ground, from Will Foster's Book. Kirkpatrick, harpsichord.
    Byrd, William, 1539 or 1540-1623. If my complaints. Kirkpatrick, harpsichord.
    Byrd, William, 1539 or 1540-1623. First Pavan. From My Lady Nevell's books. Kirkpatrick, harpsichord.
    Byrd, William, 1539 or 1540-1623. First Galliard. From My Lady Nevell's books. Kirkpatrick, harpsichord.
    Byrd, William, 1539 or 1540-1623. Sellinger's round. Kirkpatrick, harpsichord.
    Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757. Sonatas, harpsichord, K. 263, E minor. Kirkpatrick, harpsichord.
    Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757. Sonatas, harpsichord, K. 264, E major. Kirkpatrick, harpsichord.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Toccatas, harpsichord, BWV 910, F♯ minor. Malcolm, harpsichord. BBC.
    Rameau, Jean-Philippe, 1683-1764. Pièces de clavecin (1729-1730). Poule. De Robertis, harpsichord.
    Rameau, Jean-Philippe, 1683-1764. Pièces de clavecin (1729-1730). Sauvages. De Robertis, harpsichord.
    Rameau, Jean-Philippe, 1683-1764. Pièces de clavecin (1729-1730). Égiptienne. De Robertis, harpsichord.
    Rameau, Jean-Philippe, 1683-1764. Pièces de clavecin (1729-1730). Gavotte avec 6 doubles. De Robertis, harpsichord.
    Donatoni, Franco, 1927-2000. Two exercises. De Robertis, harpsichord. Spoleto festival of two worlds. 1962.
    Byrd, William, 1539or1540-1623; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Donatoni, Franco, 1927-2000; De Robertis, Mariolina; Malcolm, George, 1917-1997; Kirkpatrick, Ralph; Scarlatti, Domenico, 1685-1757; Rameau, Jean-Philippe, 1683-1764
  - Reger: Bach variations, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; full track; 7.5 ips] (Box 11, Reel 109)
    Reger, Max, 1873-1916. Variationen und Fuge über ein Thema von J.S. Bach. Johansen, piano.
    Johansen, Gunnar; Reger, Max, 1873-1916
  - Johansen: Sonatas, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; full track] (Box 11, Reel 110)
    Four improvised sonatas and one composed sonata by Johansen. The improvised sonatas are entitled: 47 - Somewhere back of Tibet; 51 - Aphoristic (excerpt); 37 - [title illegible]; 08 - Dancing [rest of title illegible]. The composed sonata is noted as being for piano and vocalist. The vocalist for this sonata is Nancy Wertsch.
    Johansen, Gunnar; Wertsch, Nancy
  - KPFA avant garde composers program; India music; Babbitt: Composition for 4 instruments, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 11, Reel 111)
    KPFA program about avant garde composers.
    BBC program, India Music. First part, South India, second part, North India.
    Babbitt, Milton, 1916-2011. Composition for four instruments.
    Babbitt, Milton, 1916-2011
  - Boulez: Pli Selon Pli. Onderdonk: Sonata for two pianos. Schäffer: Petite symphonie (Scultura), circa 1962-1966; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 11, Reel 112)
    Boulez, Pierre, 1925- Pli selon pli. Rogner, soprano; Southwest German Radio Orchestra, Boulez, conductor. First performance of complete version. Donaueschingen Festival. 1962.
    Onderdonk, Henry, 1928-2001. Sonata, pianos (2). Bussotti, Nadas, pianos. First American performance. March 21, 1966.
    Schäffer, Bogusław. Scultura. Poznan Philharmonic, Markowski, conductor.
    Markowski, Andrzej, 1924-1986; Nádas, István; Onderdonk, Henry, 1928-2001; Państwowa Filharmonia w Poznaniu; Rogner, Eva Maria; Schäffer, Bogusław; Südwestfunk (Baden-Baden, Germany). Orchester; Boulez, Pierre, 1925-; Bussotti, Carlo
  - Wuorinen: Piano variations. Del Tredici: Fantasy pieces for piano. Martino: Concerto for wind quintet, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 11, Reel 113)
    Wuorinen, Charles. Variations, piano. Wuorinen, piano.
    Del Tredici, David. Fantasy pieces.
    Martino, Donald, 1931-2005. Concertos, flute, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon. Fromm Fellowship Players, Schuller, conductor.
    Del Tredici, David; Martino, Donald, 1931-2005; Fromm Players; Schuller, Gunther; Wuorinen, Charles
  - Dallapiccola; Malipiero; Klebe; Hemel, circa 1964; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; full track] (Box 11, Reel 114)
    Dallapiccola, Luigi, 1904-1975. Parole di San Paolo. Williams, soprano; Dallapiccola, conductor. First performance. Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Memorial Concert. Washington D.C. October 30, 1964.
    Malipiero, Riccardo, 1914-2003. In time of daffodils. Roewade, soprano; Boucher, baritone; Mitchell, conductor. First performance. Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Memorial Concert. Washington D.C. October 30, 1964.
    Klebe, Giselher. Missa "Miserere nobis". Mitchell, conductor. First performance. Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Memorial Concert. Washington D.C. October 30, 1964.
    Hemel, Oscar van, 1892-1981. Tema con variazioni, orchestra. Utrecht Municipal Orchestra, Knol, conductor.
    Mitchell, Howard, 1911-1988; Malipiero, Riccardo, 1914-2003; Knol, Frits; Klebe, Giselher; Williams, Nancy; Utrecht Municipal Orchestra; Roewade, Karen; Hemel, Oscar van, 1892-1981; Dallapiccola, Luigi, 1904-1975; Boucher, Gene
  - Messiaen plays Messiaen, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips; mono] (Box 11, Reel 115)
    Messiaen, Olivier, 1908-1992. Banquet céleste. Messiaen, organ.
    Messiaen, Olivier, 1908-1992. Apparition de l'église éternelle. Messiaen, organ.
    Messiaen, Olivier, 1908-1992. Ascension, organ. Messiaen, organ.
    Messiaen, Olivier, 1908-1992
  - Alice - BBC, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 11, Reel 116)
    A BBC production of Alice in Wonderland. No other details about the recording are noted on the reel or container.
  - Homage to Shakespeare. Interview with Takemitsu. Interview with Sir Adrian Boult, circa 1963-1966; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 11, Reel 117)
    Homage to Shakespeare. Geilgud, Evans, Leighton.
    Interview with Toru Takemitsu. Ogdon, interviewer. KPFA. 1963 or 1964.
    Interview with Sir Adrian Boult. 1966.
    Leighton, Margaret, 1922-1976; Evans, Maurice, 1901-1989; Gielgud, John, John, 1904-2000; Ogdon, Will, 1921-2013; Boult, Adrian, 1889-1983; Takemitsu, Tōru
  - Sikorski, Tomasz: Sequenza I. Sikorski, Kazimierz: Bassoon Concerto. Kardoš: Symphony No.5, circa 1966; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 11, Page 118)
    Sikorski, Tomasz, 1939-1988. Sequenza I. Warsaw Festival. 1966.
    Sikorski, Kazimierz. Koncert polifoniczny.
    Kardoš, Dezider, 1914-1991. Symphonies, no. 5.
    Sikorski; Sikorski, Tomasz, 1939-1988; Kardoš, Dezider, 1914-1991
- 10.5" reels, 89 audiotape reel(s)
  - Bach: Clavier Übung III. Mozart: Sonata in D, 1962-1963; 18 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 4, Reel 29, Reel 28, Box 5, Reel 39, Reel 27, Reel 26, Reel 55, Box 3, Reel 7, Box 6, Reel 56, Reel 8, Reel 9, Reel 58, Reel 10, Reel 59, Reel 4, Reel 2, Reel 1, Reel 11, Reel 3)
    Dates
    Reel 1 - 1963-04-30; Reel 8 - 1963-08-06; Reel 9 - 1963-08-06; Reel 10 - 1963-08-06; Reel 11 - 1963-08-06; Reel 26 - 1963-08-06; Reel 27 - 1963-04-29 or 1963-04-30; Reel 28 - undated; Reel 29 - undated; Reel 39 - 1963-08-06; Reel 55 - undated; Reel 56 - undated; Reel 58 - 1963-08-06; Reel 59 - undated.
    Tapes appear to be masters. Multiple takes. Contains splices. Reel numbers assigned in the collection differ from the reel numbers assigned by the content creators.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Verschiedene Vorspiele über die Catechismus- und andere Gesaenge. Moe, organ.
    Additional content
    Reel 39 also includes the following: Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 306, D major. Shaprio, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord. February 9, 1962.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Moe, Lawrence, 1917-2013; Heinitz, Eva; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981
  - Lawrence Moe, organ, 1960-07-26; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 15 ips; stereo] (Box 3, Reel 5)
    Tape appears to a master. Contains splices.
    Moe, Lawrence, 1917-2013
  - Bach: Six Schubler Chorales, 1961-02; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 15 ips; stereo] (Box 3, Reel 6)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Choräle von verschiedener Art, BWV 645-650. Moe, organ. Hertz Hall, University of California, Berkeley. February 1-3, 1961.
    Master tape. Contains splices.
    Moe, Lawrence, 1917-2013; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750
  - Bach: Two-part inventions, 1961-08; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 15 ips; stereo] (Box 3, Reel 12)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Inventions, harpsichord, BWV 772-786. Ehlers, harpsichord.
    Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750
  - Britten: Peter Grimes, 1977; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips; two track: mono: dolby] (Box 3, Reel 13)
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Peter Grimes. Chicago Lyric Opera. Opening night. 1977.
    Possible other content
    The description for this recording is based on a slip of paper found with the reel itself. The spine of the container for the reel however suggests that the recording is of a lecture recital by Alice Ehlers captured on July 22, 1961.
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976
  - Bach: Sonatas for gamba and klavier No.1 and 2, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; stereo] (Box 3, Reel 14)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, viola da gamba, harpsichord, BWV 1027, G major. Heinitz, viola de gamba; Ehlers, harpsichord.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, viola da gamba, harpsichord, BWV 1028, D major. Heinitz, viola de gamba; Ehlers, harpsichord.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Heinitz, Eva; Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981
  - Ehlers and Heinitz, 1963-08-02; 2 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 5, Reel 37, Box 3, Reel 15)
    Container title: Ehlers-Heinitz - Reel 2, Aug 2, 1963.
  - Ehlers and Heinitz, 1963-08-04; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 3, Reel 16)
    Container title: Ehlers-Heinitz - Aug 4, 1963, Hertz Hall, Reel 3.
  - Bach: Violin and harpsichord sonata No.1; Viola da gamba sonata No.3, 1962-1963; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 3, Reel 17)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, violin, harpsichord, BWV 1014, B minor. Shapiro, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord. February 9, 1962.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, viola da gamba, harpsichord, BWV 1029, G minor. Heinitz, viola de gamba; Ehlers, harpsichord. August 4, 1963.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981; Heinitz, Eva; Shapiro, Eudice
  - Bach: Violin and harpsichord sonata No.4. Mozart: Sonata in A, 1962-02-09; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 3, Reel 18)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, violin, harpsichord, BWV 1017, C minor. Shapiro, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 305, A major. Shapiro, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord or piano.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Shapiro, Eudice
  - Wagner: Siegfried, Act 1, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; dolby] (Box 4, Reel 19)
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried. 1. Aufzug.
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883
  - Mussorgsky: Boris Godunov, 1973-10-19; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips and 3.75 ips; stereo; dolby] (Box 4, Reel 20)
    Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Boris Godunov (1869). Talvera, Godunova; Lear, Mnishek. San Francisco Opera.
    Lear, Evelyn; Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881; Talvela, Martti
  - Britten: St Nicholas cantata, 1949-11-30; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 4, Reel 21)
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Saint Nicolas. Pears, tenor; Britten, conductor. University of Southern California's Festival of Contemporary Arts. November 30, 1949.
    Additional material
    Container includes a newspaper clipping from an unknown source, entitled "Britten event wins acclaim of audience". This is a review of the performance featured on the recording, written by Albert Goldberg.
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976; Pears, Peter, 1910-1986
  - Cabrillo Festival 1971, 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 4, Reel 22)
  - Ravel: Trio. Beethoven: Trio, 1953-04-26; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 4, Reel 23)
    Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Trio, piano, violin, cello. Shapiro, violin; Gottlieb, cello; Kaufman, piano. Dabney Hall, Caltech. April 26, 1953.
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Trios, piano, violin, cello, op. 70. No. 2. Shapiro, violin; Gottlieb, cello; Kaufman, piano. Dabney Hall, Caltech. April 26, 1953.
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827; Gottlieb, Victor, -1963; Shapiro, Eudice; Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937; Kaufman, Harry, 1894-1961
  - Stravinsky concert, Los Angeles County Museum, 1954-06-27; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 4, Reel 24)
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Pastorale, soprano, piano; arranged. Shaprio, violin; Koblentz, oboe; Raimondi, clarinet; Christlieb, bassoon; Leake, english horn; Craft, conductor. Los Angeles County Museum. June 27, 1954.
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Septet, piano, clarinet, horn, bassoon, violin, viola, cello. Shaprio, violin; Raimondi, clarinet; Christlieb, bassoon; Majewski, viola; Gottlieb, cello; Decker, horn; Limonick, piano; Craft, conductor. American radio premiere. Los Angeles County Museum. June 27, 1954.
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Songs from William Shakespeare. Martin, soprano; Raimondi, clarinet; Majewski, viola; Gleghorn, flute; Craft, conductor. World radio premiere. Los Angeles County Museum. June 27, 1954.
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Tango, piano. Limonick, piano.
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Cantata. Martin, soprano; Robinson, tenor; Gelghorn, flute; Koblentz, oboe; Bergh, flute; Leake, English horn; Gottlieb, cello; Grace Notes (Chorus); Craft, conductor. American radio premiere. Los Angeles County Museum. June 27, 1954.
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971; Robinson, Richard; Shapiro, Eudice; Raimondi, Hugo; Martin, Grace-Lynn; Majewski, Virginia; Limonick, Natalie; Leake, Donald; Koblentz, Arnold; Grace Notes Womens Chorus; Gottlieb, Victor, -1963; Gleghorn, Arthur; Decker, James; Craft, Robert; Christlieb, Don; Bergh, Haakon
  - Wagner: Die Meistersinger, 1971-10-01; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips; stereo] (Box 4, Reel 25)
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Meistersinger von Nürnberg. San Francisco Opera. October 1, 1971.
  - Faure: Piano quartet, Op. 115. Bach: Sonata No.3 in E major. Mozart: Sonata in C, K.296, 1952-12-14; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 4, Reel 30)
    Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924. Quintets, piano, violins (2), viola, cello, no. 2, op. 115, C minor. Los Angeles Piano Quartet. December 14, 1952.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, violin, harpsichord, BWV 1016, E major. Murray, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord. December 14, 1952.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 296, C major. Murray, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord. December 14, 1952.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Murray, Alexander; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981; Fauré, Gabriel, 1845–1924; Los Angeles Piano Quartet
  - Bach: Sonatas for violin and piano. Mozart: Sonata, K.377, 1952-12; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 4, Reel 31)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, violin, harpsichord, BWV 1015, A major. Murray, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord. December 7, 1952.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, violin, harpsichord, BWV 1018, F minor. Murray, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord. December 7, 1952.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, violin, harpsichord, BWV 1017, C minor. Murray, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord. December 10, 1952. N.B data based on the spine of the recording's container. Another source on the container suggests that the work performed is in fact - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, violin, harpsichord, BWV 1019, G major.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Sonatas, violin, piano, K. 377, F major. Murray, violin; Ehlers, harpsichord. December 7, 1952.
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Murray, Alexander; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981
  - Beethoven: Sonata for violin and piano, Op.23. Malipiero: Rispetti e strambotti, 1953; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 4, Reel 32)
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Sonatas, violin, piano, no. 4, op. 23, A minor. Shapiro, violin; Kaufman, piano. Caltech. April 20, 1953.
    Malipiero, Gian Francesco, 1882-1973. Rispetti e strambotti. Pro Musica String Quartet. November 8, 1953.
    This tape also contains dubbed copies of the following commercial releases: Columbia, ML4956 (Antheil: Ballet Mecanique. Brant: Signs and alarms; Galaxy 2).
    Malipiero, Gian Francesco, 1882-1973; Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827; Pro Musica String Quartet; Kaufman, Harry, 1894-1961; Shapiro, Eudice
  - Stravinsky: Symphony in C. Denisov: Concerto for flute, oboe, piano and percussion. Mahler: Knaben Wunderhorn, circa 1972; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 4, Reel 33)
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Symphonies, C.
    Denisov, Ėdison Vasilʹevich, 1929-1996. Concertos, piano, flute, oboe, percussion.
    Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Knaben Wunderhorn. Baker, soprano; Shirley-Quirk, bass-baritone. San Francisco. January 14, 1972.
    Baker, Janet; Denisov, Ėdison Vasilʹevich, 1929-1996; Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911; Shirley-Quirk, John; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971
  - Berg: Lulu, 1971-11-19; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips; stereo] (Box 4, Reel 34)
    Berg, Alban, 1885-1935. Lulu. Silja, soprano. San Francisco Opera. November 19, 1971.
    Berg, Alban, 1885-1935; Silja, Anja
  - Chávez: Ten preludes. Orbon: Tres Cantigas del Rey. Barber: Lovers; Piano concerto, circa 1971; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 4, Reel 35)
    Orbón, Julián, 1925-1991. Cantigas del rey. Cabrillo Festival. 1971.
    Chávez, Carlos, 1899-1978. Preludes, piano. Cabrillo Festival. 1971.
    Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981. Concertos, piano, orchestra, op. 38
    Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981. Lovers.
    Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981; Chávez, Carlos, 1899-1978; Orbón, Julián, 1925-1991
  - Brahms: Symphony No.1, 1977-04-29; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips; two track; stereo] (Box 4, Reel 36)
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 68, C minor. San Francisco Symphony, Eschenbach, conductor. Includes interview with Eschenbach.
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897; Eschenbach, Christoph; San Francisco Symphony Orchestra
  - Bach: Viola de gamba and harpsichord sonatas No.1 and 2, 1960-08; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 15 ips; stereo] (Box 5, Reel 38)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, viola da gamba, harpsichord, BWV 1027, G major. Heinitz, viola de gamba; Ehlers, harpsichord. Carmel, CA. August, 1960.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonatas, viola da gamba, harpsichord, BWV 1028, D major. Heinitz, viola de gamba; Ehlers, harpsichord. Carmel, CA. August, 1960.
    Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Heinitz, Eva
  - Bach: Art of fugue, 1967; 6 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 5, Reel 44, Reel 43, Reel 45, Reel 40, Reel 42, Reel 41)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Kunst der Fuge. Fabrizio, harpsichord. Fabrizio, harpsichord. Town Hall, New York.
    Reel 45 includes a newspaper clipping of a review of the concert. Publication unknown.
  - Rameau: Overture. Brahms: Symphony No.1. Schoenberg: Verklarte Nacht, 1977-04-29; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 5, Reel 46)
    Rameau, Jean-Philippe, 1683-1764. Zaïs. Ouverture. San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, Eschenbach, conductor.
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 68, C minor. San Francisco Symphony, Eschenbach, conductor.
    Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951. Verklärte Nacht. San Francisco Symphony, Eschenbach, conductor.
    Eschenbach, Christoph; Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897; San Francisco Symphony Orchestra; Rameau, Jean-Philippe, 1683-1764; Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951
  - Sweelinck; Buxtehude; Bach; Pachelbel, 1961-10-10; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 15 ips; full track; mono] (Box 5, Reel 47)
    Sweelinck, Jan Pieterszoon, 1562-1621. Toccata in A. Talsma, organ. Zorgvlietkerk, Scheveningen, Den Haag.
    Buxtehude, Dietrich, 1637-1707. [Title of work undecipherable]. Talsma, organ. Zorgvlietkerk, Scheveningen, Den Haag.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Kleine Präludien und Fugen. BWV 560 only. Talsma, organ. Zorgvlietkerk, Scheveningen, Den Haag.
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Choräle von verschiedener Art, BWV 651-668. An Wasserflüssen Babylon. Talsma, organ. Zorgvlietkerk, Scheveningen, Den Haag.
    Pachelbel, Johann, 1653-1706. Musicalische Sterbens-Gedancken. Christus, der ist mein Leben. Talsma, organ. Zorgvlietkerk, Scheveningen, Den Haag.
    Additional contents
    Includes a letter from and undecipherable source to the recording engineer, dated January 28, 1963.
    Sweelinck, Jan Pieterszoon, 1562-1621; Talsma, Willem Retze; Buxtehude, Dietrich, 1637-1707; Pachelbel, Johann, 1653-1706; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750
  - Mendelssohn: Trio. Kohs: Quartet, 1954-02-21; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; half-track] (Box 5, Reel 48)
    Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Trio. Coleman Chamber Music audition winners. Pasadena Playhouse.
    Kohs, Ellis B., 1916-2000. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello. Coleman Chamber Music audition winners. Pasadena Playhouse.
    Kohs, Ellis B., 1916-2000; Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847